Guide to the Fantasy Magazine Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Fantasy Magazine papers
1929-1979
YCAL MSS 55
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7
(11 boxes)
The Fantasy Magazine Papers consist of manuscripts, correspondence, and other materials documenting the life of the magazine.
Fantasy Magazine
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Fantasy Magazine Papers were purchased in 1989 from Joseph A. Dermont with monies from the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 10-11: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
FANTASY MAGAZINE
Fantasy magazine was begun in the summer of 1931 by Stanley Dehler Mayer in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. This "little magazine" was intended to be a forum for the publication of "good free verse." Issued initially as a quarterly, Fantasy invited submissions from its readership and featured several Pennsylvania poets in its first issues, among them Homer D'Lettuso and Joseph Leonard Grucci. In its first number, the magazine offered a five dollar prize for the best essay on a living American poet published in the magazine. Though these essays appeared frequently during the first years of publication, their regularity decreased after 1933. A longer-standing tradition was Fantasy 's poetry contest in each issue. Contestants were required to write on a particular theme (e.g., "Christmas," "Night," and "Nudism"), vying for a five dollar prize and publication in the front of the magazine. Judges for the contests included Edgar Lee Masters and Stephen Vincent Benét. The winner of the poem contest on the theme of "The Negro," Lewis H. Fenderson, gained a certain notice because he was an African-American.
Beginning in 1933, the magazine expanded its scope to include short stories and longer essays from such writers as James T. Farrell and LeGarde S. Doughty. Mayer's brief section of comments on new works of poetry expanded into a full book review section, containing signed reviews from the likes of Lloyd Mallan and Charles Glicksberg. Along with the changing format came a broadened scope of coverage on literary themes. The first issue for 1938 included an essay on "Convict Poetry" and featured submissions from prisoners, among them the issue's prizewinner, Ralph W. Hunter. By 1941, Fantasy had featured an essay on Surrealism by Eugene Jolas and one on "Paging the 'Western' Novelist" by Arnold Mulder.
By the end of the 1930s, the magazine had a contingent of contributing poets and writers from around the United States. Included among them were Kenneth Patchen, August Derleth, Harlan Hatcher, Harry Roskolenko, Joseph Joel Keith, and Harvey Breit. The magazine also had connections with writers' communities in Santa Fe, New Mexico, and California, as evidenced by contributions from Witter Bynner, Haniel Long, and James Neill Northe.
A regular feature of the magazine, translations of foreign-language poets, became of primary importance when, in 1942, Fantasy began to present a separate section on Latin American literature. Working with the Pan American Union and the Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin America (based in New Haven), Mayer published poetry and stories by Spanish-language writers such as Angel Flores, Enrique Mendez Calzada, and Regino Pedroso. Works by Pablo Neruda, Octavio Paz, and Hugo Manning were also included in this section. This new format was used for the final two issues in 1942 and 1943.
Stanley Dehler Mayer (1909-) credited Ralph Cheyney of Contemporary Vision and Jack Conroy of The Rebel Poet with assistance in starting Fantasy. Mayer contributed essays to The New Hope, a short-lived critical magazine published in New Hope, Pennsylvania in the 1930s, and printed some of his own verse in the first issues of Fantasy. The attention Fantasy garnered allowed Mayer to expand the size of the magazine. Fantasy began in 1931 with 22 pages; the final issue had 150. Though literary advertisements began to be placed as Fantasy 's reputation grew, Mayer had difficulties in producing issues on a regular basis because of financial limitations. The numbering of issues is irregular beginning in 1937, when single issues were published for each year. This lasted until the magazine's demise in 1943. During the run of the magazine, Mayer established a relationship with James Laughlin, a Pittsburgh native who would later start New Directions Publishing Company. Laughlin, inspired by the presence of a little poetry magazine in his hometown, sought out young poets to publish in his own magazine. Among these were Dylan Thomas and Paul Eluard, whose works were also submitted by Laughlin to Mayer for publication in Fantasy. Many of the Spanish language poets who were first published in Fantasy were later included in the New Directions collection, Anthology of Contemporary Latin-American Poetry edited by Dudley Fitts in 1942.
Mayer, who had been involved in the printing trade before and during the period he published Fantasy, entered the U. S. Army in 1943. He eventually returned to his original profession after the war. He published no further issues of Fantasy, but did solicit interest in the late 1960s for a reissue of the original run of the magazine.
Scope and Contents
The Fantasy Magazine Papers document the life of a "little magazine" dedicated principally to "free verse" poetry. The papers consist of correspondence, manuscript submissions, photographs, clippings, printed works, and financial and legal documents. The papers span the years 1929 to 1979, with the bulk of material falling within the years of the magazine's publication, 1932-43.
The collection is housed in 10 boxes and consists of three series: I. Correspondence; II. Manuscript Submissions; and III. Other Papers. Box 9 contains oversize material from Series III. Box 10 contains restricted fragile papers.
Series I, Correspondence (Boxes 1-4) covers the years 1931-79 and documents the interaction between Fantasy 's editor, Stanley Dehler Mayer, and contributing writers, subscribers, editors of other little magazines, and publishing houses. The bulk of the correspondence consists of letters from writers hoping to be published in the magazine. A significant number of the remaining letters are from persons concerned with the survival of the magazine, either subscribers, fellow publishers, or literary aficionados.
The majority of letters from writers submitting their work are brief, direct queries which occasionally include personal information about the writer. Kenneth Patchen's letters discuss his submissions and inquire about the status of Mayer's induction into the army. Harvey Breit, a friend of Patchen's, mentions the poet in his own letters. Harry Roskolenko's correspondence discusses versions of his work submitted to Mayer and suggests friends who would be likely to submit work or subscribe to Fantasy. Other correspondents include: Carl Burkland, writing about his love of Keats and Whitman; Herman Salinger, who translated poems by Rilke and Christian Morgenstern for Fantasy; Joseph Joel Keith, writing from Hollywood about his achievements and those of associates Kathleen Sutton, Don Blanding, and Irl Morse; Regis Kausler, who suggests that Fantasy become formally associated with the [Walt] Whitman Society of America; and LeGarde S. Doughty, who forwarded a copy of a letter he sent to William Carlos Williams refuting observations Williams made in "To Write American Poetry," an essay published in Fantasy. The letters of Pauline Frances Stephens and Eleanor Tawnley contain digressions on subjects other than poetry, particularly Stephens's discussion of the vanity of poets and Tawnley's description of a flood in Cincinnati.
A second subject of correspondence concerns publication of the magazine. Letters can be found from Charles Henri Ford, publisher of View, from Ada McCormick, publisher of Letter, and from Bennett Cerf, who replied to Mayer that a novel about a jazz band would be "virtually negligible" in 1940. Mayer's work in introducing Latin American writers to North American readers can be traced in letters from the Pan American Union, the Coordinator for Inter-American Affairs, and the Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin America, all correspondents who directed Mayer to worthy poets and writers. Lloyd Mallan, who corresponded independently in addition to his service with the Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin America, suggests that Mayer could increase his rapport with his growing Latin American clientele if he improved his language skills. A professional correspondent who seems to have had more personal connections to Mayer and his wife, Portia, is Grace K. Wellington. Her letters concerning her publication, Troubadour, branch out into more diverse topics. A 1935 letter discusses her opinions of other little magazines, most specifically the implications of getting published in the Communist-inspired New Masses. The letter then goes on to provide gardening tips.
Series II, Manuscript Submissions (Boxes 5-7), consists of works sent to Stanley Mayer to be considered for inclusion in Fantasy. The series contains poetry, essays, reviews, and short stories, most of which are undated. The poetry ranges from the evenly measured stanzas of Stanton Coblentz to the meandering constructions of Clark Mills. Alex Comfort writes about war and the passage of time, while Waring Cuney made terse transcriptions of black dialects. Included here are Kenneth Patchen's multipart "Seven Poems About the Way to Go Out of the World"; Lloyd Mallan's collection of poems, "A Tear for the Virgins of Mind and Soul"; and a corrected copy of Kenneth Rexroth's "For Andrée Rexroth." Other poets represented include: Edgar Lee Masters, Eve Merriam, Robin Lampson, Oscar Williams, Haniel Long, and Joseph Leonard Grucci. Among the Latin American poets are Pablo de Rokha, Jacinto Fombona Pachano, Pablo Neruda, and Regino Pedroso.
Essays submitted include Carmelo Bonet's work on Latin criticism, "Apuntaciones sobre el Arte de Juzgar" [translated], Arundell del Re on Ezra Pound; Charles Glicksberg on "Proletarian Poetry in the United States"; and James Hargan's "Convict Poets," which was used in an issue of Fantasy that featured poetry by prisoners. Book reviews were contributed by, Winfield Townley Scott, Wallace Stegner, and Arthur E. DuBois. William Carlos Williams contributed a commentary on Kenneth Patchen's The Journal of Albion Moonlight. The short fiction selected for Fantasy consisted mainly of narratives by the likes of James T. Farrell, Weldon Kees, Gilbert Nieman, Meridel LeSeur, and Jean Temple. Of the Latin American contributions, Enrique Mendez Calzada's "Christ in Buenos Aires" was featured in one of the final issues of Fantasy.
Series III, Other Papers, contains newspaper clippings and a small number of miscellaneous items, such as bills, receipts, copyright certificates, and two photographs. The clippings were taken from publications which mentioned Fantasy or which included material by Fantasy 's contributors. Such publications include the Augusta Chronicle, the Columbia, Ohio Dispatch, the New Mexico Sentinel, the Pittsburgh Press, and the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette.
Box 9 contains Oversize material from Series III. Included are copies of The New Day, a newspaper published in the Ohio State Reformatory, and clippings from the New York Times, the Bulletin Index, and the New Mexico Sentinel.
Fantasy (Pittsburgh); American literature -- 20th Century -- Periodicals; Latin American literature -- 20th Century -- Periodicals; Little magazines; Periodicals -- Publishing; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Prisoners -- Poetry; Publishers and publishing; Authors; Editors; Poets; Breit, Harvey; Burkland, Carl Edwin; Bynner, Witter, 1881-1968; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971; Coblentz, Stanton A. (Stanton Arthur), 1896-1982; Comfort, Alex, 1920-2000; Derleth, August, 1909-1971; D'Lettuso, Homer; Doughty, LeGarde S.; Du Bois, Arthur Edwin, 1904-1965; Éluard, Paul, 1895-1952; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979; Ford, Charles Henri, 1908-2002; Glicksberg, Charles I. (Charles Irving), 1900-1998; Grucci, Joseph Leonard, 1908-1982; Hatcher, Harlan, 1898-1998; Kees, Weldon, 1914-1955; Keith, Joseph Joel; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997; Long, Haniel, 1888-1956; Macleod, Norman, 1906-1985; Mallan, Lloyd; Masters, Edgar Lee, 1868-1950; Mayer, Stanley Dehler; McCormick, Ada P.; Mills, Clark, 1913-; Nemerov, Howard, 1920-1991; Patchen, Kenneth, 1911-1972; Roskolenko, Harry, 1907-1980; Scott, Winfield Townley, 1910-1968; Stuart, Jesse, 1906-1984; Thomas, Dylan, 1914-1953; Wellington, Grace K.; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963; Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin America; Pan American Union
- Correspondence, 1931-79; Series I; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by name of author, then chronologically. Undated correspondence is placed after dated correspondence. Correspondents having three or more letters are listed by name. Correspondents having fewer then three letters are included in the "Letter" general files.
  - "A" general, 1933-42, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbe, George, 1936-43, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ackley, Edith, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allison, Brent, 1933, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Amberg, George, 1936-39, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The American Mercury
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Lawrence Spivak, Box 4 folder 195
  - Anderson, Helen (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anderson, J. Redwood, 1936, [1940?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Anvil
    See: Jack Conroy, Box 1 folder 43
  - Armour, Richard, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arnold, E. G., 1934-37 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Associated Negro Press, 1936-37 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "B" general, 1934-70, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baker, Glen, 1936-41, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Beals, Carleton, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Beck, Warren, 1940-41 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Benét, William Rose, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Benton, Walter, 1939-42 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bernstein, David, 1935-36 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Better Verse (magazine)
    See: Irl Morse, Box 2 folder 152
  - Bishop, John Peale, 1936-43 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Blanding, Don (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bragdon, Clifford, 1933-34, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bramlett, William, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Braybrooke, Neville, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Breit, Harvey, 1939-41, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brinnin, John Malcolm, 1934, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Brown, Harry, 1935, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Brown, Leonard, 1938-40 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Buck, Ashley, 1936-42 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Burke, Henry, 1941-42 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Burkland, Carl Edwin, 1933-39 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Burridge, Gaston, 1935-37 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1940-42 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "C" general, 1932-71, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Caldiero, F. St. M., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Cane, Melville, 1938-43 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Carrera Andrade, Jorge, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Caxton Printers, 1935-38 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Cerf, Bennett, 1934-40 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1935, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Coblentz, Stanton, 1934-37, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Coffin, Robert P. Tristam, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Comfort, Alex, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin America, Inc., 1942-43 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    See also: Lloyd Mallan, Box 3 folder 137
  - Compass: A Journal of Modern Verse
    See: James A. Decker, Box 1 folder 52
  - Conroy, Jack, 1931-33, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs
    See: United States. Office for Emergency Management. Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, Box 4 folder 215
  - Council Against Intolerance in America, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Craig, Maurice James, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Creighton, Alan, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Crews, J. C., 1936-40 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Cuney, Waring, 1936, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "D" general, 1935-42, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Davis, Dorothy M., 1935-37 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Decker, Duane, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Decker, James A., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - DeJong, David C., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Derleth, August, 1934-42, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 54-55)
  - Division of Cultural Relations
    See: United States Dept. of State. Division of Cultural Relations, Box 4 folder 214
  - D'Lettuso, Homer, 1935-38, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - D'Nova, 1937, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Doughty, LeGarde S., 1935-40 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Doyle, Marian, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - DuBois, Arthur E., 1935-58, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Duncan, Ronald, 1937, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Duncan, Thomas W., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - "E" general, 1935-44 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Eaton, Charles Edward, 1939-69 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Eberhart, Richard, 1941-69 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Ebright, Frederick, 1936-41 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Ellison, Ralph, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Ellson, Hal, 1936, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - "F" general, 1934-43, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Farbstein, W. E., 1939-41 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Farrell, James T., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Faust, George T., 1938, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Flores, Angel, 1941-43, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Foley, Martha, 1941-42 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Ford, Charles Henri, 1940-43 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Forkin, Katherine, 1937-38, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Friedrich, Ralph, 1935-40 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - "G" general, 1935-43, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Gessler, Clifford, 1936, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Gill, D. Sanial, 1936-39, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Gillett, Lucie Karme, 1934-38, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Giniger, Weldon, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Glicksberg, Charles, 1935-43 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Gotham Book Mart, 1939-43 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Grucci, Joseph Leonard, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Gustafson, Ralph, 1940-41 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - "H" general, 1934-70, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Hagen, Victor Wolfgang von, 1941-42 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Hargan, James, 1936-38 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Harrison, Henry, 1933, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Harriss & Givens, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Hatcher, Harlan, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Hays, H. R., 1941, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Haywood, Terence, 1939-40 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Hendler, Earl, 1940, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Higgins, John Lee, 1935-36, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Honig, Edwin, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Hudeberg, Charles, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Hughes, Langston, 1935, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Humphrey, G. W., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Humphries, Rolfe, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Hunter, J. Stewart, 1938-40, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - "I" general, 1934, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Isaacs, Leo, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - "J" general, 1935-59, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Johnson, James Weldon, 1936, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Johnson, Marie, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Jolas, Eugene, 1940-41 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Jones, Putnam Fennell, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - "K" general, 1934-58, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Kausler, Regis, 1935-36 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Kees, Weldon, 1935-41, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Keith, Joseph Joel, 1935-40, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Kelm, Karlton, 1935, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Kirby, Marshall, 1935-36 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Klopfer, Donald S., 1936-37 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Kozlenko, William, 1937, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Kresensky, Raymond, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - "L" general, 1933-41 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Lampson, Robin, 1935-39 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Laughlin, James, 1935-42, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Lehman, Milton, 1938-43, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - LeSeur, Meridel, 1933, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Letter
    See: Ada McCormick, Box 2 folder 134
  - Lewis, James Franklin, 1941-42 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Lieberman, Elias, 1933-41 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Light, David H., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Litsey, Edwin Carle, 1933-37 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Litsey, Sarah, 1935-36 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - The Little Man
    See: Robert Lowry, Box 2 folder 131
  - Lodge, Evan, 1936-38, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Long, Haniel, [1932?]-42, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 130)
    See also: James H. Maguire, Box 2 folder 136
  - Lowry, Robert, 1939-40 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Lyric
    See: J. R. Moreland, Box 2 folder 151
  - "M" general, 1934-72, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - McCarthy, John Russell, 1937-42 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - McCormick, Ada, 1943-44 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - MacLeod, Norman, 1938-39, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Maguire, James H., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Mallan, Lloyd, 1939-43, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Manch, Joseph Rodman, 1936-39 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Mangan, Sherry, 1937-38 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Mann, Stella Lucia, 1940, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Manning, Hugo, 1940-42, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - May, James Boyer, 1939-41 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Meeter, George F., 1934, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Merriam, Eve, 1940-41 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Merrill, Alice Louise, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Miller, Fred R., 1932, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Mills, Clark, 1935-42, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Hill, 1935-36 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Monroe, Harriet, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Moody, Minnie Hite, 1933-35 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Moore, Nicolas, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Morang, Alfred, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Moreland, J. R., 1933-36, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Morse, Irl, 1935, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - Moser, Alice, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - Mulder, Arnold, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Musser, Ben, 1932-35, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - "N" general, 1932-42, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - Neagoe, Peter
    See: Donald S. Klopfer, Box 2 folder 116
  - Neider, Charles, 1942-43 (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - The Negro Quarterly
    See: Ralph Ellison, Box 1 folder 67
  - New Directions
    See: James Laughlin, Box 2 folder 121
  - The New Mexico Quarterly Review
    See: Allan Swallow, Box 4 folder 202
  - New York Public Library, 1938, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Nieman, Gilbert, 1939-41 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Norman, Dorothy, 1941, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Northe, James Neill, 1935-38, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Nutt, Howard, 1940-41 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - "O" general, 1935, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - O'Brien, Edward J., 1933, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - "P" general, 1934-40, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Pan American Union, 1942, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Panetta, George, 1941-42 (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Paquette, Donald J., 1935-39, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Patchen, Kenneth, 1936-43, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - Patchen, Miriam, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - People's Bookshop, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - Peterson, William, 1941, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Pierce, Rosamond F., 1935-36 (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Pierce, T. M., 1940 (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Pillin, William, 1939-42, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Poetry, A Magazine of Verse
    See: Harriet Monroe, Box 3 folder 149
  - Poetry Society of America
    See: Harold Vinal, Box 4 folder 221
  - Poetry World and Contemporary Vision
    See: Henry Harrison, Box 2 folder 90
  - Posner, Harry
    See: D'Nova, Box 1 folder 57
  - Quinn, John Robert, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - Quinn, Kerker, 1935, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - Quinn, Leo A., 1934-74 (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - "R" general, 1935-41, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - Random House
    See: Bennett Cerf, Box 1 folder 37
  - The Rebel Poet
  - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Re, Arundell del, 1938-39 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Rhys, Keidrich, 1939, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - Richeson, Janet Andrews, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 176)